[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
*
- * Founder's Day
is here today. *
- * 创始人日
今天就在这里。 *
Squidward, is this even?
章鱼哥，这还算平吗？
- A little higher.
- 高一点。
A little to the left.
向左一点。
A little more to the left.
再往左边一点。
Ha!
Perfect.
哈!
完美的。
Oh.
哦。
- [humming wildly]
- [疯狂哼唱]
*
- Whoa, Mr. Krabs
really loves Founder's Day.
- 哇哦，蟹老板
真的很喜欢创始人日。
- No, he doesn't.
- 不，他没有。
- But just look at him go.
- 但只要看着他就走。
- This is the day
he gets the patty orders
- 这一天
他得到了肉饼的订单
for the big Founder's Day
eating contest.
庆祝伟大的创始人日
饮食比赛。
It's the most money
Krabs makes all year.
这是最多的钱
螃蟹全年都在生产。
- Oh, but it's not just that.
- 哦，但不仅仅是这样。
Mr. Krabs has a lot of love
in his heart for this town.
蟹老板有很多爱
他心里对这个小镇。
- Nope, Squidward's right.
- 不，章鱼哥是对的。
Not only do I supply
the eating contest,
我不仅供应
饮食大赛，
but I get to sell
me profit-laden patties
但我可以卖掉
我的利润丰厚的馅饼
to all the hungry spectators.
致所有饥饿的观众。
I had to grease a few wheels,
but it was worth it.
我得给几个轮子涂润滑油
但这是值得的。
- Thanks, Krabs!
- 谢谢，蟹蟹！
- Sure thing,
Mr. Commissioner.
- 当然可以，
专员先生。
See you at Founder's Day.
创始人日见。
[coughs]
[咳嗽]
* Oh, I wonder, wonder, wonder
how many patties must we make *
*哦，我想知道，想知道，想知道
我们必须做多少个肉饼 *
- Wonder no longer.
- 不再好奇了。
You only need one.
你只需要一个。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
What do you mean "one"?
你说的“一”是什么意思？
- Didn't you see
today's newspaper?
- 你没看到吗
今天的报纸？
- "No Takers
for McNulty Challenge."
- “没有接受者
麦克纳尔蒂挑战赛。”
Ha! What is that
supposed to mean?
哈!那是什么
应该是什么意思？
- He's the current champion.
- 他是目前的冠军。
He only needs to eat
one patty to win.
他只需要吃饭
一块肉饼就赢了。
- [gasps]
I'm ruined.
- [喘气]
我毁了。
No one wants to see
a one-patty eating contest,
没有人愿意看到
一场吃肉饼比赛，
least of all me wallet.
最重要的是我的钱包。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- Hey, at least we have
Founder's Day.
- 嘿，至少我们有
创始人日。
- I couldn't give a sea fig
for Founder's Day.
- 我不能给海无花果
创始人日。
I need sales, boy.
我需要销售，小伙子。
Sales is what I need.
销售是我所需要的。
Oh, if only there was someone
dumb and hungry enough
噢，要是有人就好了
又蠢又饿
to take on
old Oswald McNulty.
承担
老奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂。
- I'll just have
47 Krabby Patties, please.
- 我只要
请给我 47 个蟹黄饼。
I had a big breakfast
so I'm not that hungry.
我吃了一顿丰盛的早餐
所以我没那么饿。
Squidward, did you get
a new haircut?
章鱼哥，你得到了吗？
新发型？
- Ah, dumb and hungry.
- 啊，又蠢又饿。
Well, if it isn't Patrick.
好吧，如果不是帕特里克的话。
- I isn't Patrick?
- 我不是帕特里克？
- No, no, of course you ares.
- 不，不，你当然是。
How would you like to eat
你想吃什么
as many Krabby Patties
as you can handle
和蟹肉饼一样多
你可以处理的
and restore the honor
of your hometown?
并恢复荣誉
你家乡的？
- I like the first part,
- 我喜欢第一部分，
but I don't understand
the second part.
但我不明白
第二部分。
- I'm talking
about Oswald McNulty.
- 我在说话
关于奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂。
He comes here every year
with his big-city ways
他每年都会来这里
以他的大城市风格
and his extremely relaxed
throat muscles,
和他极其放松的
喉咙肌肉，
and he shows us up
like a bunch of rubes.
他向我们展示了
像一群乡巴佬。
Rubes!
鲁布斯！
And on Founder's Day,
no less.
在创始人日那天，
不少。
[bell dinging]
[铃声]
We need a hometown hero
to make me lots of money.
我们需要一位家乡英雄
让我赚很多钱。
I mean, return the belt
to Bikini Bottom.
我的意思是，把腰带还给我
到比基尼底部。
[chuckles nervously]
[紧张地笑]
You're going up
against the best,
你要往上走
对抗最优秀的人，
so you have to be the best.
所以你必须是最好的。
We're going to light a fire
under you, boy-o.
我们要生火
在你之下，小伙子。
- Oh, no,
that's going to hurt!
- 哦，不，
那会很痛！
- Listen up, mister.
No more fooling around.
- 听着，先生。
别再胡闹了。
You're here to eat and eat
你来这里是为了吃吃吃
and then eat some more.
然后再吃一些。
- I like to eat.
- 我喜欢吃。
- Well, let's see how your tummy
handles these patties,
- 好吧，让我们看看你的肚子怎么样
处理这些肉饼，
Mr. Likes To Eat.
先生喜欢吃。
- [laughs]
You said "tummy."
- [笑]
你说的是“肚子”。
- Tummy!
- 肚子！
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[whistle blows]
[哨声响起]
- I like whistles!
- 我喜欢口哨！
- Eat!
- 吃！
- Oh.
- 哦。
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
- What are you doing?
You're wasting time.
- 你在干什么？
你在浪费时间。
- Got to warm up
my taste buds first.
- 必须热身
首先是我的味蕾。
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Son,
can you eat faster?
- 儿子，
你能吃快点吗？
- Oh, faster.
- 哦，快点。
- Four and a half patties
in one minute?
- 四个半肉饼
一分钟内？
Why, McNulty can eat
100 in a minute.
为什么，麦克纳尔蒂可以吃东西
一分钟100。
But, you know,
I think your teeth
但是，你知道，
我觉得你的牙齿
might be getting in the way
a little bit there.
可能会妨碍
那里有一点点。
- Oh,
why didn't you say so?
- 哦，
你为什么不这么说？
- Ooh, I didn't know
you had false teeth.
- 哦，我不知道
你有假牙。
- [laughs]
I don't.
- [笑]
我不知道。
- Nah, that can't be it.
- 不，不可能是这样。
McNulty has teeth.
麦克纳尔蒂有牙齿。
SpongeBob,
let's go to the film.
海绵宝宝，
我们去看电影吧。
Look at that devious face,
看看那张阴险的脸，
a face without pity--
一张没有怜悯的脸——
cold, dead eyes,
like a shark's eyes.
冰冷、死气沉沉的眼神，
像鲨鱼的眼睛。
What is Oswald McNulty doing
that Patrick Star is not?
奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂在做什么
那帕特里克星不是吗？
- His homework?
- [gasps]
- 他的作业？
- [喘气]
Or maybe we should be asking,
或者也许我们应该问，
what is Oswald McNulty
not doing?
奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂是什么
不做什么？
- His taxes?
- 他的税？
- You're both wrong!
Or possibly right.
- 你们都错了！
或者可能是对的。
I mean, I don't know much
about his personal life.
我的意思是，我知道的不多
关于他的个人生活。
The point is,
he's not tasting, boys.
重点是，
他没有品尝，孩子们。
That's where
Oswald McNulty has the edge.
那就是那里
奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂有优势。
Those extra seconds you take
to taste the patty, Patrick,
你多花的那几秒
品尝肉饼，帕特里克，
are slowing you down.
正在减慢你的速度。
From now on, you must pop them
in your mouth and swallow.
从现在开始，你必须弹出它们
放入口中并吞咽。
- I don't get to taste?
- 我没机会尝尝？
- This feels wrong,
Mr. Krabs.
- 这感觉不对，
蟹老板。
- Stow that bilge water,
bucket boy.
- 存放舱底水，
水桶男孩。
We're going to need
100 more patties.
我们将需要
还有100个肉饼。
- Okay, I'll get
right on it.
- 好的，我会得到
就在上面。
- We're going to teach
this sea star a new way to eat--
- 我们要教书
这种海星的新吃法——
without tasting.
无需品尝。
all: No!
全体：不！
[inspiring music]
[鼓舞人心的音乐]
*
[growls]
[咆哮]
Oh!
[munching wildly]
哦！
[疯狂地咀嚼]
- There he goes!
- Our champion!
- 他走了！
- 我们的冠军！
- He's so dreamy!
- 他真是太有梦想了！
- Oh!
- 哦！
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
- Come one, come all.
- 一个都来，大家都来。
This Sunday, Sunday, Sunday.
这周日，周日，周日。
It's a Founder's Day
eating extravaganza.
今天是创始人日
饮食盛宴。
Watch your hometown hero,
Patrick Star,
关注家乡的英雄，
帕特里克·斯塔,
take on the malevolent mouth
from three towns over,
恶毒的嘴
来自三个以上的城镇，
Oswald McNulty
奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂
and see who takes
the Patty Belt.
看看谁拿走
帕蒂腰带。
- Say, can my little boy
ask you something?
- 说，我的小男孩可以吗？
问你什么事吗？
- [muffled speech]
- [低声说话]
- Are you the brave man
that's going
- 你是勇敢的人吗
就这样
to bring the belt back
to Bikini Bottom?
把皮带带回来
到比基尼底部？
- [muffled speech]
- [低声说话]
- Inspiring words.
- 鼓舞人心的话语。
- I "hurted" my foot
on the playground.
- 我的脚“受伤了”
在操场上。
- Yeah, yeah, that's wonderful.
Move back.
- 是的，是的，那太棒了。
向后移动。
Be sure to bring
your friends.
一定要带
你的朋友们。
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
[crowd booing]
[人群嘘声]
- Dad, is that the bad man
who took the belt away
- 爸爸，那是坏人吗
谁拿走了腰带
from Bikini Bottom?
来自比基尼底部？
- Yes, it is, son.
Boo!
- 是的，是的，儿子。
嘘！
- Boo!
- 嘘！
- It looks like this crowd
is hungry...
- 看起来就像这群人
饿了……
for excitement, that is,
为了兴奋，也就是说
and also possibly food.
也可能是食物。
Any moment now,
these doors will open
现在任何时刻，
这些门将会打开
on what promises to be the most
dynamic patty-eating contest
关于什么是最有希望的
动态吃馅饼比赛
in Founder's Day history.
在创始人日的历史上。
- Krabby Patties,
T-shirts, conical hats,
- 蟹黄饼，
T恤、圆锥形帽子、
and Patrick's choppers.
和帕特里克的直升机。
- Today our local hero,
Patrick Star,
- 今天我们当地的英雄，
帕特里克·斯塔,
the courageous underdog,
is going up
勇敢的失败者，
正在上升
against five-time belt winner
Oswald McNulty,
对阵五冠王
奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂,
from three towns over.
来自三个城镇以上。
One can only imagine
the seething tension
人们只能想象
沸腾的紧张
boiling over right now
现在沸腾了
between these two titans
of the sport
在这两个泰坦之间
这项运动的
as they prepare
for ultimate battle.
当他们准备时
为了最终的战斗。
[insects chirping]
- Hey.
[昆虫鸣叫]
- 嘿。
- How's it going?
- 怎么样了？
- Five short minutes to consume
as many patties as they can.
- 短短五分钟即可食用
尽可能多的肉饼。
- Who's ready?
- 谁准备好了？
- SpongeBob,
I don't want to do this.
- 海绵宝宝，
我不想这样做。
- Well, then don't do it.
- 好吧，那就别这么做了。
I'm sure Mr. Krabs
will understand.
我确信蟹老板
会明白的。
- [sniffs]
I smell mutiny.
- [嗅嗅]
我闻到了叛变的味道。
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事？
- I don't want to eat
in the contest.
- 我不想吃饭
在比赛中。
It hurts my taste feelings.
它伤害了我的味觉感受。
[all sobbing]
[全都抽泣]
- Hmm.
No problem.
- 唔。
没问题。
Here.
- What's that?
这里。
- 那是什么？
- That is a bill for all
the Krabby Patties you ate
- 这是所有人的账单
你吃的蟹黄饼
during training.
训练期间。
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
- But I didn't know
I had to pay.
- 但我不知道
我必须付钱。
- Well, I didn't know either
- 嗯，我也不知道
until you decided
you weren't doing the contest,
直到你决定
你没有参加比赛
and that means
all your "training" patties
这意味着
你所有的“训练”馅饼
just became plain
eatin' patties.
刚刚变得平淡
吃肉饼。
Now, if you was
to do the contest,
现在，如果你是
参加比赛，
I might be inclined to tear up
this here little bill,
我可能会想流泪
这张小账单，
and, of course, there are
all the people
当然，还有
所有人
that are counting
on you, son.
正在计数的
在你身上，儿子。
[all cheering]
- Ow, my foot.
[大家欢呼]
- 噢，我的脚。
- Okay, I'll do it for the
little boy with the hurt foot.
- 好的，我会做的
脚受伤的小男孩。
- You made
the right choice, kid.
- 你做了
正确的选择，孩子。
[laughs]
[笑]
- There's the bell.
And we're off and eating.
- 铃响了。
我们就出发去吃饭了。
McNulty taking an early lead
麦克纳尔蒂早早取得领先
and really going to work
on those patties.
并真正去上班
在那些肉饼上。
What a dynamo!
多么强大的发电机啊！
The little smelt
from three towns over
小的闻到了
来自三个以上的城镇
eating at a terrific pace.
吃东西的速度非常快。
But what's this?
Patrick Star isn't moving.
但这是什么？
帕特里克·斯塔没有动。
He seems stuck at the gate.
他似乎被困在门口了。
- What are you doing,
Patrick?
- 你在做什么，
帕特里克？
Don't make me charge you
for those patties too!
别让我向你收费
还有那些馅饼！
- McNulty's pressing forward.
- 麦克纳尔蒂正在向前推进。
Looks like this
is going to be a blowout.
看起来像这样
将会是井喷。
- Patrick,
I believe in you, Patrick.
- 帕特里克，
我相信你，帕特里克。
- But wait!
Patrick Star is on the move,
- 但是等等！
帕特里克·斯塔正在行动，
and patties are
starting to disappear.
和肉饼是
开始消失。
Look at that
little sea star eat!
看看那个
小海星吃饭啦！
He's inching closer to McNulty,
他离麦克纳尔蒂越来越近了
and it looks like McNulty
can feel the heat.
它看起来像麦克纳尔蒂
可以感受到热量。
Never has there been
a more prodigious display
从来没有过
更精彩的展示
of competitive eating.
竞争性饮食。
The amount of patties
being consumed is astounding.
肉饼的份量
被消耗的程度是惊人的。
[all whimpering]
[全都呜咽]
And now, yes, yes,
现在，是的，是的，
Patrick Star has matched
Oswald McNulty,
帕特里克·明星 已匹配
奥斯瓦尔德·麦克纳尔蒂,
and they are tied as they
come into the homestretch.
他们被绑在一起
进入最后冲刺阶段。
Both eaters are now so full,
两个食客现在都吃饱了，
they can barely eat,
but eat they do.
他们几乎无法进食，
但他们确实吃。
Moving so slowly now,
one can't help but wonder
现在动作这么慢，
人们不禁想知道
if they are going to hit the
patty wall at some point,
如果他们要击中
帕蒂墙在某个时刻，
and--and...
还有——还有……
both eaters have stopped!
两个吃东西的人都停下来了！
With only seconds left,
we are tied in patties eaten,
只剩下几秒钟的时间，
我们被绑在吃的肉饼上，
and neither one seems
to have the room to go on.
似乎没有人
有空间继续下去。
Oh!
What's this?
哦！
这是什么？
And down goes McNulty!
Down goes McNulty!
麦克纳尔蒂倒下了！
It looks like
we could have a tie.
看起来像
我们可以打平手。
- It's over, SpongeBob.
I can't go on.
- 结束了，海绵宝宝。
我无法继续下去了。
- The taste, Patrick.
Remember the taste.
- 味道，帕特里克。
记住味道。
- The... taste.
- 味道。
- What's this?
- 这是什么？
Patrick Star has risen
from his seat
帕特里克之星已经升起
从他的座位上
and is pointing
to center field.
并指着
到中场。
No, wait. He's pointing to
"widdle" boy with a hurt foot.
不，等等。他指着
脚受伤的“中间”男孩。
Ladies and gentlemen,
he's pointing to his mouth
女士们、先生们，
他指着他的嘴
as if to indicate something.
仿佛在暗示着什么。
- Here you go, champ.
You can have mine.
- 给你，冠军。
你可以拥有我的。
[taste buds cheering]
[味蕾欢呼]
- And he's eating.
He's eating!
- 他正在吃东西。
他正在吃东西！
The Great Starbino
is eating!
伟大的斯塔比诺
正在吃饭！
Patrick Star wins!
帕特里克星获胜！
The belt is back
in Bikini Bottom!
腰带又回来了
在比基尼底部！
The belt is back
in Bikini Bottom!
腰带又回来了
在比基尼底部！
- Here you go, son.
You earned it fat and square.
- 给你，儿子。
你赢得了它又肥又方。
- Yay!
- 耶！
- Congratulations,
Starbino.
- 恭喜，
斯塔比诺。
So are you going to defend
the belt next year?
那么你要捍卫吗
明年的腰带？
- No, this thing
doesn't even fit.
- 不，这个东西
甚至不适合。
- Ow!
My other foot.
- 噢！
我的另一只脚。